desertschools.org 2010-06-16

# Desert Schools | Privacy Policy

Desert Schools Federal Credit Union is a financial cooperative owned by its members and overseen by an elected, volunteer Board of Directors. Your financial privacy is a top priority of this credit union. The credit union is required by law to provide its members with this privacy notice to explain how we collect, use and safeguard your personal financial information. If you have any questions, please contact a member service representative at (602) 433-7000.

We are committed to providing you with competitive products and services to meet your financial needs, which necessitates that we share information about you to complete your transactions and to provide you with certain financial opportunities. In order to do so, we have entered into agreements with other companies that provide either services to us or additional financial products for you to consider.

Under these arrangements, we may disclose all of the information we collect from the sources and of the type described below, to companies that perform marketing or other services on our behalf, or on behalf of us and another financial institution, or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. To protect our members' privacy, we only work with companies that agree by contract to maintain strong confidentiality protections and limit the disclosure and use of information we provide only to carry out the purposes for which such information was disclosed. We do not permit these companies to sell to other third parties the information we provide to them.

We also share information based solely on our experiences or transactions with you with our affiliated third party financial services provider, Desert Schools Financial Services, which provides investment and insurance services.

**Information We Collect And Disclose About You**

We collect the following nonpublic personal information about you from the sources described below. We may disclose all the information we collect of the type, and from the sources described below, to our affiliated company as well as companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or on behalf of us and another financial institution, or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements.

  * From membership and loan applications and other forms, we obtain information such as name, address, social security number and income.
  * From your transactions with us, our affiliate, or other companies that work closely with us to provide you with financial products and services, we obtain information such as your account balances, payment history, parties to transactions, and credit card usage.
  * From consumer reporting agencies, we obtain information such as your creditworthiness and credit history.
  * From verifications of information you provide on applications and other forms, we obtain information from current or past employers, other financial institutions and other sources listed on the application.

We may also disclose information we collect about you under other circumstances as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include information to process transactions on your behalf, conduct the operations of our credit union, follow your instructions as you authorize, or protect the security of your financial records.

If you terminate your membership with Desert Schools Federal Credit Union, we will not share information we have collected about you, except as permitted or required by law.

**How We Protect Your Information**

We restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees who have a specific business purpose in utilizing your data. Our employees are trained in the importance of maintaining confidentiality and member privacy. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations and leading industry practices to safeguard your nonpublic personal information.

**eCommunications**

Upon opting into ecommunications via our Web site, you grant Desert Schools permission to send our monthly enewsletter—the _Desert Schools Insider_ —and occasional email updates with valuable offers to your designated email address. If you wish to opt-out of ecommunications, simply click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email message you received.

Enrolling in ecommunications is separate from Online Banking. Opting in or out of ecommunications will not impact your account information or the email address on file for eStatements, Account Alerts or other Online Banking features. In addition, Desert Schools reserves the right to contact you via email to answer your questions, facilitate an application, fulfill disclosure requirements and service your account(s).
